<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>KubeCon on </title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/kubecon/</link>
    <description>Recent content in KubeCon on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/kubecon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Four KubeCon &#43; CloudNativeCon Schedules for Four Types of Attendees</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/four-kubecon--cloudnativecon-schedules-for-four-types-of-attendees/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/four-kubecon--cloudnativecon-schedules-for-four-types-of-attendees/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;KubeCon is one of those huge events where so much is happening, and so much is happening at the same time. If you don&amp;rsquo;t&#xA;plan in advance, you&amp;rsquo;re very likely to miss out on some events that would have been interesting for you. Our first tip&#xA;is: don’t worry too much about missing talks, as all talks will be recorded and uploaded to YouTube shortly after the&#xA;event. Social events, workshops, discussions etc. cannot be caught up later.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Discover mirrord’s approach to fast, cloud-connected local dev at KubeCon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/discover-mirrords-approach-to-fast-cloud-connected-local-dev-at-kubecon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/discover-mirrords-approach-to-fast-cloud-connected-local-dev-at-kubecon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We get it—“Another blog about a company’s KubeCon booth?” These posts can be a bit predictable. So, we’ll keep this one brief and focused on how &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirrord.dev/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34; &gt;&#xA;    mirrord&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;   can actually make cloud development easier.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As one CTO put it, “&lt;em&gt;at our company, mirrord is doing as much for developer productivity as AI is&lt;/em&gt;.” That’s high praise, and while we’re not here to boast, we do think it’s worth checking out if you’re looking for a smoother development process.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KubeCon 2024 Takeaways</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/kubecon-2024-takeaways/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/kubecon-2024-takeaways/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last month marked a huge milestone for us as we attended our first KubeCon! This was KubeCon Europe, which took place in Paris, city of lights and cloud orchestration. Below is a summary of our collective impressions and insights.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;co-located-events-and-surprising-highlights&#34;&gt;Co-Located Events and Surprising Highlights &lt;a href=&#34;#co-located-events-and-surprising-highlights&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We arrived a day before KubeCon proper started so we could attend the co-located events. We ended up mostly going to AppDeveloperCon sessions, and it was surprisingly crowded. Our highlight from the first day was Daniel Bryant’s excellent talk &lt;strong&gt;“&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3tP31j_T6IE&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34; &gt;&#xA;    Testing Cloud Apps: Mocks vs. Service Virtualization vs. Remocal Tools&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;  ”&lt;/strong&gt;. Daniel covered our favorite pain - being unable to work against a real environment and iterate with it as part of the development workflow. We were pleased to see a very friendly shoutout to mirrord and our to talk later in the convention!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
