<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mirrord-for-Teams on </title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/mirrord-for-teams/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mirrord-for-Teams on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 06:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/mirrord-for-teams/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>mirrord for Teams – a Step Into the Remocal Future</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/mirrord-for-teams-a-step-into-the-remocal-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/mirrord-for-teams-a-step-into-the-remocal-future/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/blog/mirrord-for-teams-a-step-into-the-remocal-future/mftlaunch.png&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;      Today we’re excited to announce that after two years of development on mirrord Open Source, our tool that enables Remocal development for Backend engineers, we’re releasing &lt;em&gt;mirrord for Teams&lt;/em&gt; to bring that awesome power to entire Engineering organizations. If you’re new to the term, Remocal development combines the best of both worlds of the dominant modern cloud software engineering paradigms – &lt;em&gt;Remote&lt;/em&gt; development, where you maintain no local environment and everything is cloud dependent, and &lt;em&gt;Local&lt;/em&gt; development, where you develop software on your computer, sync code to staging and production, and test. &lt;em&gt;Remocal&lt;/em&gt; development allows developers to work locally while their process &lt;em&gt;thinks&lt;/em&gt; it is running remotely on Staging – and it’s done via a bit of magic we call mirrord. If a tool for shortened software development lifecycles and better collaboration for backend developers, packaged as an enterprise-ready platform with security and governance features included could help you, read on – we think you’ll be very interested in &lt;em&gt;mirrord for Teams&lt;/em&gt;. But first, a bit about how we got there.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
