<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open-Source on </title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/open-source/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Open-Source on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/open-source/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Discover mirrord’s approach to fast, cloud-connected local dev at KubeCon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/discover-mirrords-approach-to-fast-cloud-connected-local-dev-at-kubecon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/discover-mirrords-approach-to-fast-cloud-connected-local-dev-at-kubecon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We get it—“Another blog about a company’s KubeCon booth?” These posts can be a bit predictable. So, we’ll keep this one brief and focused on how &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirrord.dev/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34; &gt;&#xA;    mirrord&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;   can actually make cloud development easier.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As one CTO put it, “&lt;em&gt;at our company, mirrord is doing as much for developer productivity as AI is&lt;/em&gt;.” That’s high praise, and while we’re not here to boast, we do think it’s worth checking out if you’re looking for a smoother development process.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>There and Back Again: Port Forwarding with mirrord</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/there-and-back-again-port-forwarding-with-mirrord/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/there-and-back-again-port-forwarding-with-mirrord/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;port-forwarding-in-the-wild&#34;&gt;Port forwarding in the wild &lt;a href=&#34;#port-forwarding-in-the-wild&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Port forwarding via SSH, also called SSH tunneling, is a method for communicating securely over an insecure connection. In this way sensitive info can be transmitted over the internet, for example to access your company&amp;rsquo;s testing environment data from home.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/blog/there-and-back-again-port-forwarding-with-mirrord/ssh-port-forwarding.png&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;diagram of SSH port forwarding&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;More recently, port forwarding might also refer to &lt;code&gt;kubectl port-forward&lt;/code&gt;, allowing the user to forward traffic into a Kubernetes cluster from a local port by going through the Kubernetes API. This is a faster way to access a pod without having to write special configuration to set up ingress or a service, but is generally considered “just good enough” for lightweight debugging.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Validation at Scale with Open Source MVPs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/validation-at-scale-with-open-source-mvps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/validation-at-scale-with-open-source-mvps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;      Minimum Viable Products (MVPs) are generally accepted as the right way to kickstart a product startup. It’s easy - you whip up a quick prototype, get it in front of some users, and boom - you’ve got some feedback plus an initial user base. All that’s left to do is iterate for a few years until you reach Unicorn status. What’s often left unaddressed in this version of the story is - &lt;em&gt;how do you get users for your MVP, and in a large enough amount that their feedback isn’t skewed or overfitted&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal-who?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/metal-who/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/metal-who/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;metalbear&#34;&gt;MetalBear!🐻 &lt;a href=&#34;#metalbear&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A huge omnivore that also conducts electricity. In the present context, though, a new startup that’s working on developing a new toolset for backend engineers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-&#34;&gt;Why ⏪ &lt;a href=&#34;#why-&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Like many devtools startups, MetalBear was born out of frustration. We&amp;rsquo;ve both spent years building cloud services, splitting up monoliths, wrangling configurations, writing endless tests only to break production because of that one edge case.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We finally came to the realization that while tools tailored to devops engineers, frontend developers, QA engineers, and more, we, the backend developers, were being underserved. So much of our day to day work seemed needlessly slow or complicated, begging for automation or even fundamental disruption, and yet no company seemed willing to rise up to the challenge. So we decided to start MetalBear 🐻&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
