<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Platform-Engineering on </title>
    <link>http://localhost:54350/tags/platform-engineering/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Platform-Engineering on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:54350/tags/platform-engineering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bear in Mind #1: Platform Engineering</title>
      <link>http://localhost:54350/blog/bear-in-mind-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:54350/blog/bear-in-mind-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;      At MetalBear we build open-source dev tools for backend developers, which puts our domain at the intersection of some pretty interesting topics. There&amp;rsquo;s still a lot of great content being written about things that aren&amp;rsquo;t AI - things like Kubernetes, DevEx, Open Source, Rust, and more - and we go through a lot of it as part of our daily work. How easy it would then be, we collectively thought, to provide our growing community of curious but busy backend developers with a periodic, curated list of our favorite pieces of writing on these topics?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KubeCon 2024 Takeaways</title>
      <link>http://localhost:54350/blog/kubecon-2024-takeaways/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:54350/blog/kubecon-2024-takeaways/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last month marked a huge milestone for us as we attended our first KubeCon! This was KubeCon Europe, which took place in Paris, city of lights and cloud orchestration. Below is a summary of our collective impressions and insights.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;co-located-events-and-surprising-highlights&#34;&gt;Co-Located Events and Surprising Highlights &lt;a href=&#34;#co-located-events-and-surprising-highlights&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We arrived a day before KubeCon proper started so we could attend the co-located events. We ended up mostly going to AppDeveloperCon sessions, and it was surprisingly crowded. Our highlight from the first day was Daniel Bryant’s excellent talk &lt;strong&gt;“&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3tP31j_T6IE&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34; &gt;&#xA;    Testing Cloud Apps: Mocks vs. Service Virtualization vs. Remocal Tools&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;  ”&lt;/strong&gt;. Daniel covered our favorite pain - being unable to work against a real environment and iterate with it as part of the development workflow. We were pleased to see a very friendly shoutout to mirrord and our to talk later in the convention!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparison of Internal Developer Platforms</title>
      <link>http://localhost:54350/blog/comparison-of-internal-developer-platforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:54350/blog/comparison-of-internal-developer-platforms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;DevOps emerged to address the need for better developer productivity and a more efficient development lifecycle. However, DevOps teams often find themselves bogged down by operational tasks like security, scaling, and infrastructure management. The demand for robust developer platforms continues to grow, and with the rise of cloud computing, organizations struggle to keep pace with the complexities and speed involved. This is where Internal Developer Platforms (IDPs) come in – a trendy concept in Platform Engineering that promises to streamline processes and boost developer productivity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five Talks We&#39;re Waiting for at KubeCon Europe 2024</title>
      <link>http://localhost:54350/blog/five-talks-were-waiting-for-at-kubecon-europe-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:54350/blog/five-talks-were-waiting-for-at-kubecon-europe-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bonjour Kubernauts! Kubecon Europe is less than a month away, and it’s coming to the city of lights. The MetalBear team will be joining the fun in Paris this year, and we’ve prepared a list of five talks that we’re particularly excited about.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;center mid-width&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:54350/blog/five-talks-were-waiting-for-at-kubecon-europe-2024/kubecon-paris.png&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;mirrord at KubeCon Europe 2024&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;whats-new-at-kubecon-this-year&#34;&gt;What’s New at KubeCon This Year? &lt;a href=&#34;#whats-new-at-kubecon-this-year&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every year, the event unveils transformative tech trends that are making waves in the tech ecosystem, causing end-users, developers, engineers, and stakeholders to reflect on the past and how these trends can impact their future.&#xA;KubeCon + CloudNativeCon 2024 promises to spotlight several groundbreaking projects that have flourished within the Kubernetes ecosystem. Unsurprisingly, the main buzzword this year is AI.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Approaches in Cloud Development Ergonomics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:54350/blog/approaches-in-cloud-development-ergonomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:54350/blog/approaches-in-cloud-development-ergonomics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The advent of microservice architectures and cloud-native has taken some pretty severe tolls on developer ergonomics. It feels as if the tools cloud developers have at their disposal haven’t evolved fast enough to keep up with the rapid progress in infrastructure, and this tool debt is readily apparent in the day-to-day of the modern developer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The clearest example of this is that it’s now &lt;strong&gt;really hard to just run your application&lt;/strong&gt;. Not the one microservice you’re currently working on, but your actual entire application, which you ultimately deploy to the cloud and serves your customers. You used to be able to fire up your monolith right there on your laptop from within your IDE (crash, change some code, run it again), but architectures today have become resource-intensive, reliant on third-party services, and mostly just plain convoluted to the point where local execution is no longer a viable option.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
